Register of the Gaston Bergery papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Gaston Bergery papers
1909-1973
77069
Hoover Institution Archives
44 manuscript boxes, 1 envelope (18.4 linear feet)
Correspondence, telegrams, reports, memoranda, lists, speeches and writings, and leaflets relating to French political events and foreign relations, France during World War II, and the Front Populaire.
Bergery, Gaston, 1892-1974.
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1977.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1892 November 22 Born, Paris, France
1912 Received bachelor's degree in law
1914 Enlisted; wounded in 1915
1916 Liaison with the British Army
1917 Decorated with the Military Cross for distinguished services
1918 Attached to the Secretariat of the Versailles Peace Conference
1918-1924 Deputy Secretary-General of the Inter-Allied Commission for Reparations
1920 Married Germaine Malançon
1924 Decorated with the Legion of Honor
1924 Delegate to the London Conference
1924-1925 Director of the Cabinet of Edouard Herriot, Minister of Foreign Affairs
1925 In charge of a mission to the United States
1926 Attorney, Court of Appeals, Paris (specialized in private international law)
1927 Married Lubov Krassin; son Jean-François raised by her in London after she and Bergery divorced in 1928
1928 Founded the daily Mantes Republicain
1928-1934 Deputy of the Seine-et-Oise (radical-socialist party); Member, Committee on Foreign Affairs
1935-1939 Founded and directed the weekly La Flèche
1936-1942 Deputy ( frontiste party, which he founded with Jacques Izard)
1934 Married Elisabeth (Bettina) Shaw-Jones
1937 Author, Air-Afrique, Voie Impériale
1938 Author, Notre Plan, Principes de l'Economie Frontiste
1940 November Sent on a mission to Switzerland by the Ministry of Foreign Affairs
1941 April-June Ambassador to the Soviet Union
1942 June - 1944 September Ambassador to Turkey
1945 Returned voluntarily to France; Tried, Court of Justice, Paris - Acquitted in 1949
1947 Resumed legal career
1948 Author, La Vierge et le Sagittaire (under the pseudonym of Gaston François)
1957-1958 Columnist for the daily Paris-Presse l'Intransigeant ( Libre Chronique Diplomatique)
1969 Retired
1974 Died
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, telegrams, reports, memoranda, lists, speeches and writings, and leaflets relating to French political events and foreign relations, France during World War II, and the Front Populaire.
Inter-Allied Commission for Reparations.; Inter-allied Conference on Reparations and Inter-allied Debts (1924: London, England).; Communism--France.; Elections--France.; World War, 1914-1918--Reparations.; World War, 1939-1945--France.; Europe--Politics and government--1918-1945.; France--Colonies.; France--Foreign relations.; France--Foreign relations--Soviet Union.; France--Foreign relations--United States.; France--History--German occupation, 1940-1945.; France--Politics and government--20th century.; Soviet Union--Foreign relations--France.; United States--Foreign relations--France.; Diplomats--France.
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1911-1963 (Boxes 1-7)
  Scope and Contents note
  Correspondence, legal documents pertaining to Bergery's trial, and membership cards, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Biographical data (Box 1)
  - Decorations - Legion of Honor
  - Dedications to Bergery by friends of his, written on the title pages of their books
  - Homes, decoration of
    Mostly correspondence regarding art works.
    - Mantes
    - Paris
  - Invitations
  - Membership cards, passes, etc.
  - Miscellaneous
  - Programs, menus, etc.
  - Trial
    - General (Box 2)
    - Brief for the defense, 2 folders
    - Correspondence with the High Court (Box 3)
    - Detention
    - Documents, 3 folders
    - Honor Jury, 2 folders
    - Interrogation
    - Memoranda for the defense
    - Memoranda for the defense, 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Note to the press
    - Photocopies of various items, 2 folders
    - Press accounts
      - 1945-1946 (Box 5)
      - 1946
      - 1949, 2 folders
      - 1949 (Box 6)
    - Testimonies
      - For the defense, 6 folders
      - For the prosecution (Box 7)
      - Mixed
      - Not used
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1909-1969 (Boxes 7-11)
  Arrangement note
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - Unidentified (Box 7)
  - With readers
  - General
  - Adamthwaite, Anthony P., 1963
  - Alexandre, Michel, 1933-1938
  - Allais, Emile, 1940-1954
  - Aron, Robert, 1941-1949
  - Ashton-Gwatkin, F., 1957
  - Aymard, Camille, 1961
  - Barbusse, Henri [See SUBJECT FILE, Comité Mondial de Lutte Contre la Guerre Impérialiste and Comité National de Lutte Contre la Guerre et le Fascisme]
  - Bauer, Gerard, 1955
  - Becourt, Gilbert, 1941-1963
  - Beistegui, Charlie, 1955-1959
  - Benes, Edouard, 1924
  - Benoîist-Mechin, Jacques, 1957-1963
  - Bergery, Bettina (third wife), 1945-1966
  - Bergery, Franc (brother), 1939-1966
  - Bergery, Jean-François (son), 1946-1965
  - Bergery-Derocle, Marie-Louise (mother), 1913-1918 (Box 8)
  - Berl, Emmanuel, 1927-1958
  - Bernier, Jean, 1916-1969
  - Berthelot, Philippe, 1925-1926
  - Beucler, Philippe, n.d.
  - Bloch, Jean-Richard, 1934
  - Boll, André, 1939-1966
  - Bourg de Bozas, du, 1925
  - Bourguiba, Habib, 1934-1955
  - Brondet, F., 1957
  - Bugatti, Ettore, 1930
  - Cate, Curtis, 1967
  - Challaye, Félicien, 1942-1959
  - Chambrun, René de, 1947-1967
  - Clair, René, 1950
  - Clérisse, Henry, 1950
  - Club du Faubourg, Paris, 1927-1934
  - Colonna d'Istria, T., 1909-1911
  - Comité Français de Coopération Démocratique, 1928
  - Copeland, George, undated
  - Corre, Max, 1957-1963
  - Couve de Murville, Maurice, 1967
  - Cudenet, Gabriel, 1928-1933
  - Delannoy, Marcel, 1941-1948
  - Dijour, Mlle, 1948-1949
  - Drieu La Rochelle, Jean, 1952
  - Drieu La Rochelle, Pierre, 1922-1931
  - Dubois, André, 1941-1942
  - Durand, Fernand, 1942
  - Duret, F., 1957
  - Eddy, 1911-1929
  - Enrenburg, Ilya, undated
  - Emery, Léon, 1939-1942
  - Enfière, André, 1942
  - Erkin, Behic, 1947-1960
  - Fabre, Jean, 1941
  - Fabre-Luce, Alfred and Lolotte, 1933-1962
  - Falize, André, 1964
  - Figueras, Louis, 1939-1941
  - Fitz George, France, 1950-1954
  - Foras, D. de, 1950
  - Foucaud, Lucien Pierre, 1941-1948 (Box 9)
  - Foulon, Pierre, 1914-1964
  - François-Poncet, Andre, undated
  - Fulconis, Noël, 1940-1964
  - Galtier-Boissière, Jean, 1949-1965
  - Garet, Jean-Louis, 1965-1966
  - Garnier, Editions, undated
  - Gaulthier, Charles, 1941
  - Gilbert, S. Parker, 1925-1927
  - Guitard, Louis [See SPFECHES AND WRITINGS, Radio Broadcast]
  - Guyon, Robert [See also Temps de Paris and Tixier-Vignancourt, Jean-Louis], 1948-1963
  - Herbette, Jean, 1925
  - Herrick, Myron T., 1925
  - Herriot, Edouard, 1924
  - Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace, Stanford, 1954
  - Hunebelle, André, 1941-1968
  - Isorni, Jacques, 1947-1966
  - Izard, Georges, 1942-1961
  - Jallu, Marie-Claude, 1959-1966
  - Jamet, Claude, 1964
  - Jardin, Jean, 1947-1960
  - Jayle, Christian, 1963
  - Jeanson, Henri, 1941-1966
  - Jeramec, Colette, undated
  - Jmouroff, Georges, 1942
  - Jolly, Jean, 1961
  - Jouvenel, Bertrand de [See also SUBJECT FILE, France, Foreign Relations, Italy], 1932-1959
  - Jouvenel, Hélène de, 1960s
  - Jouvenel, Henry de, undated
  - Joxe, Françoise, 1956
  - Juin, Maréchal, 1952
  - Keiswin (?), Phyllis, 1911
  - Keyserling, Comtesse Wilhelmine, 1955
  - Kinross, Lord, 1960
  - Krassine, Katia, 1958
  - Krassine, Lubov (second wife), 1929-1934
  - La Rochefoucauld, Duchesse Edwina de, 1962
  - La Rochefoucauld, Comte Stanislas de, 1931-1941
  - Labonne, Eirik, 1928-1962
  - Lacouture, Jean, 1961
  - Lacroix, André, 1955
  - Lamar, Alice de, 1950
  - Lanux, Pierre and Eyre (?), undated
  - Larmour, Peter, 1960
  - Laroche, Henri, 1925
  - Larrieu, Marcelle, 1959-1963
  - Larroumets, René, 1948
  - Lasell, Philip, 1957
  - Laurens, 1927
  - Leroy-Ladurie, Jacques, 1953
  - Lefranc, Georges, 1936
  - Liander, P., 1941
  - Loucheur, Louis, 1922
  - Lurcat, Jean, undated
  - Madariaga, Salvador de, 1937-1939 (Box 10)
  - Malançon, Germaine (first wife), 1920s
  - Marcepoil, Charles, 1952-1957
  - Marie, André, 1937-1965
  - Martin du Gard, Maurice, 1928
  - Martin du Gard, Roger, undated
  - Martivale, C., 1954-1956
  - Mauriac, Claude, 1954
  - Maurois, André, undated
  - Ménétrel, Bernard, 1946
  - Meyer, Fernand, 1942
  - Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Paris, 1949-1956
  - Miravittles, Jaume, 1956
  - Molinier, Henri, 1939-1941
  - Monod, Thérèse, 1936
  - Montigny, Jean, 1924-1968
  - Montseny, Frederica, 1941
  - Monzie, Anatole de, 1925-1941
  - Morand, Paul, 1935-1962
  - Moucheboeuf, Leon C., 1941-1952
  - Moucheboeuf, Wladimir, 1941-1956
  - Moulin de la Barthète, H. du, 1941
  - Mun, Comte Antonin de, 1957
  - Naldi, Filippe, 1963
  - Nat, Daniel, 1942
  - Noailles, Vicomte Charles de et Marie-Laure, 1946-1966
  - Offner, Bernard, 1967
  - Olesia, Pierre, 1930
  - Oswald, Marianne, 1949-1963
  - Pannetier, Odette, 1959
  - Papen, Franz von, 1961
  - Paris-Presse L'Intransigeant, Paris [See also Corre, Max], 1959
  - Patino, Christina, 1958
  - Pétain, Maréchal, 1941
  - Petitjean, Michel, 1942-1954
  - Pinay, Antoine, 1964
  - Poincaré, Raymond, undated
  - Polignac, Marquis Dalmas de, 1941
  - Polignac, Comtesse Jean de (Marie-Blanche), 1955
  - Pomereu, Marquis Armand de, 1950-1962
  - Pomereu, Marquise Lydie de (born de Mun), 1947-1961
  - Pomereu, Comte Robert de, 1942-1954
  - Porel, Jacques, 1927
  - Powel, Gretchen, 1953-1960
  - Prade, Georges, 1957
  - Prévost, Jack, 1941
  - Rappoport, Charles, 1939-1941
  - Reboul, Jacques, 1956
  - Reibel, Charles, 1954
  - Rheims, Maurice, 1964
  - Ripper, Evelyn von, 1962-1963
  - Ristelhueber, Boulos (?), 1957
  - Rivain, Jean, 1941-1942
  - Rivollet, Georges, 1965-1967
  - Robbe, Fernand, 1957-1965
  - Roche, Emile, 1948-1957
  - Rubio, Fernando A., 1954-1965
  - Scapini, Georges, 1949-1966 (Box 11)
  - Schiaparelli, Elsa, 1959
  - Scott, Georges, 1912
  - Sellier, Henri, 1942
  - Sert, José-Maria, 1935-1941
  - Sforza, Comte, 1936
  - Simon, Georges, 1914-1919
  - Spreckles, Dorothy, 1951
  - Tartavez, Edmond, 1941-1942
  - Temps de Paris, Paris, 1956
  - Ter-Oganessoff, Sarkis, 1950
  - Tixier-Vignancourt, Jean-Louis, 1957
  - Torrès, Henry, 1924-1933
  - Vanwelkenhuyzen, Jean, 1965-1966
  - Vatican, Annonciature Apostolique du, 1958-1961
  - Vieillard, Pierre, 1948
  - Weiss, Louise, 1923
  - Wright, Cobina, 1958-1959
  - Wyler, Clarisse, 1969
  - Wyler, Jean-Jacques, 1955
  - Zeltin, O., 1929-1932
  - Zerray, Jean, 1942
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1907-1958 (Boxes 11-14)
  Articles, diaries, books, declarations, editorials, essays, poetry, speeches, arranged alphabetically by title.
  See also CORRESPONDENCE, Pétain, Maréchal; SUBJECT FILE, Ambassadorships of Bergery, Turkey; Chamber of Deputies; Conseil National; L'Europe Nouvelle; French Mission; League of Nations; Mission to America; Reparations, Inter-Allied Commission for.
  - Unidentified (Box 11)
  - Air-Afrique (Air Africa), Paris, 1937
    - Correspondence
    - Reviews - clippings
  - Articles - typewritten and printed copies
    - List of people to whom to send articles
    - General
      - 1932-1933
      - 1935
      - 1936-1938
      - 1956-1958 (Box 12)
      - 1965
    - Published in Arts, Paris, 1954-1955
    - Published in Mantes Républicain, Mantes
      - 1928
      - 1929
      - 1930
      - 1931
      - 1932
      - 1933
      - 1934
      - 1938-1940
  - "Aux Français de Bonne Volonté" (To Frenchmen of good will) - typewritten copy of a political appeal, 1951
  - "Conte pour le 21 Mars" (Tale for the 21st of March) - handwritten copy, 1907 or 1908
  - "Déclaration sur l'Assemblée Nationale" (Declaration on the National Assembly) - typewritten carbon copy and printed copy, 1940
  - Diary - handwritten copy, 1914
  - "Effets de Neige" (Snow effects) - printed copy of an essay, published in Primavera, Paris, 1909
  - "Français!" (Frenchmen!) - typewritten carbon copy of a political appeal, undated
  - Interviews - typewritten carbon copies and printed copies, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - "Lettre" (Letter) - typewritten carbon copy of a political appeal, undated
  - "Libre Chronique Diplomatique" (Free diplomatic chronicle) - typewritten carbon copies and printed copies of daily columns published in Paris-Presse L'Intransigeant, Paris, 1957-1958
  - Literary criticism - handwritten and typewritten notes
  - "Le Mal Français" (The French disease) - typewritten copy of a political appeal, undated
  - "Note sur la Politique en Afrique du Nord" (Note on politics in North Africa) - typewritten carbon copy of an analysis intended for Marechal Petain, 1942
  - 1938
  - 1935
  - "Le Pays Mantais" (The "Mantais" country) - typewritten carbon copy of a speech, and printed excerpts published in L'Echo des Touristes, Paris, 1932
  - Poems - handwritten and typewritten copies
  - Radio broadcast on "Europe No.1" - typewritten transcripts of a talk given by Bergery on the fall of France in June 1940, the Vichy government, the Resistance, etc. and of the interview which followed, 1965
  - "Ski 1946. Essai sur le Matériel, la Technique et l'Enseignement" (Ski 1946. Essay on the equipment, the technique and the instruction) - handwritten and typewritten copies of a manuscript, 3 folders
  - "Soir d'Hiver" (Winter evening) - printed copy of an essay published in Primavera, Paris, 1909 (Box 14)
  - Speeches
    - 1932
    - 1933
    - 1934
    - 1937
    - 1938 or 1939
    - 1949
    - 1953
    - 1966
    - Miscellaneous - correspondence
  - La Vierge et le Sagittaire (The virgin and the archer), Paris - handwritten draft, including sketches
  - La Vierge et le Sagittaire (The virgin and the archer), Paris - printed copy, 1948 (Box 15)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1915-1973 (Boxes 15-30)
  Conference proceedings, correspondence, election material, financial studies, memoranda, printed matter, and reports, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Africa (Box 15)
    - General
    - Bergery's trip to French Equatorial Africa, 1936
  - Ajam, Maurice
  - Algeria
  - Ambassadorships of Bergery
    - Soviet Union, 1941
    - Turkey, 1942-1944
      - General
      - Speeches
  - Association pour Défendre la Mémoire du Maréchal Pétain
  - Auphan, Amiral
  - Barney, Natalie Clifford
  - Bastien-Thiry
  - Belin, René
  - Bergery, Bettina [See also Le Colis du Combattant Mantais]
  - Bergery, Franc
  - Bergery-Derocle, Marie-Louise
  - Biaggi, Jean-Baptiste
  - Blum, Léon [See also France, Foreign relations, Italy]
  - Bourguiba, Habib
  - Brasseur, Pierre
  - Briand, Aristide
  - Céline, Louis Ferdinand (Box 16)
  - Chamber of Deputies, Paris
    - General
    - Correspondence
    - Documents, 2 folders
    - Groups
    - Leagues
    - Speeches
    - Unions ("unions parlementaires")
  - Chambrun, René de (Box 17)
  - Churchill, Winston
  - Cocteau, Jean
  - Le Colis du Combattant Mantais. Comité d'Aide aux Soldats de l'Arrondissement de Mantes
  - Comité d'Aide aux Emigrés et Réfugiés d'Allemagne
  - Comité Mondial de Lutte contre la Guerre Impérialiste
  - Comité National de Lutte contre la Guerre et le Fascisme
  - Communism, 2 folders
  - Conference of the Hague [See also Rhineland], 1930; 4 folders
  - Conference of London, 1924 (Box 18)
    - General
    - Documents, 2 folders
    - Final protocol
    - Minutes of meetings, 2 folders
  - Conseil de l'Ordre des Avocats, Paris (Box 19)
  - Conseil National
    - Commission d'Etude de la Région Parisienne
    - Commission d'Etude des Questions de Jeunesse
    - "Rapport Spécial sur le Tourisme Hivernal" (Special report on winter tourism)
  - Le Crapouillot, Paris
  - Debts, World War I [See also Reparations, Inter-Allied Commission for]
    - German
    - Interallied, 4 folders
  - Debts and reparations. Studies
  - Disarmament
  - Drieu La Rochelle, Jean
  - Elections, municipal and legislative
    - 1928, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - 1932, 2 folders
    - 1934, 4 folders
    - 1936, 3 folders (Box 21)
    - 1954
    - 1955
    - 1956, 2 folders
    - 1956 (Box 22)
  - Estrade, Georges
  - Europe - Colonies
  - L'Europe Nouvelle, Paris
  - Fabre-Luce, Alfred [See also Pamphlet] (Box 23)
  - La Flèche [See Parti frontiste]
  - France [See also Chamber of Deputies, Conseil National, Elections, Ministry of Foreign Affairs]
    - General
    - Foreign relations
      - Czechoslovakia
      - Germany
      - Great Britain
      - Italy
    - History
      - See CORRESPONDENCE, Larmour, Pierre, 1934, February 6
      - 1940
      - 1944
    - Vichy government
  - French Mission attached to the British Army, 1917
  - Front Commun, voice of the Mouvement frontiste [See Parti frontiste]
  - Frontisme [See Parti frontiste]
  - Fulconis, Noël
  - Galtier-Boissière, Jean
  - Gaulle, General Charles de
  - Great Britain [See also France, Foreign relations, Great Britain]
  - Guiness, Patrick
  - Herriot, Edouard [See also Pamphlet]
  - Hitler, Adolf
  - Indochina (Box 24)
  - Informations, Paris
  - Inter-Allied Commission for Reparations [See Reparations, Inter-Allied Commission for]
  - International private law
  - Kipling, Rudyard
  - Krassin, Leonid Borisovitch
  - Lamartine, Alphonse de
  - Laval, Pierre
  - League of Nations [See also Disarmament]
  - Ligue des Droits de l'Homme
  - Ligue Internationale des Combattants de la Paix
  - London Conference [See Conference of London]
  - Malraux, André
  - Mantes Républicain. Administrative correspondence
  - Marie, André
  - Marti, Ada
  - Mauriac, François [See Cocteau, Jean]
  - Maurras, Charles
  - Mérimée, Prosper
  - Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Paris
    - General
    - Congratulations to Bergery upon his appointment as Chief of Cabinet
  - Miscellaneous, 2 folders
  - Mission to America, Bergery's report, 1925
  - Monnet, Henri (Box 25)
  - Munich - Crisis of 1938
  - Mussolini, Benito [See France, Foreign relations, Italy]
  - Pamphlet, Paris
  - Parti frontiste
    - General, 2 folders
    - Assises Nationales Extraordinaires, 1935 July 6 and 7
    - La Flèche, voice of the Parti frontiste, 2 folders
    - Notre Plan. Principes de l'Economie Frontiste, 1938
  - Parti républicain radical et radical-socialiste (Box 26)
    - Committees
    - Congresses, 3 folders
    - Correspondence
    - Executive Committee
    - Resignation of Bergery from parliamentary group, 1929
  - Pétain, Maréchal Philippe [See also Churchill, Winston]
  - Radical-socialism [See Parti républicain radical et radical-socialiste]
  - Radkoff-Rajnof
  - Rappoport, Charles
  - Reading notes (literature, philosophy, etc.)
  - Reichstag - Burning, 1933 (Box 27)
  - Reparations, Inter-Allied Commission for
    - Correspondence, notes
    - Documents, 3 folders
    - Documents, 2 folders (Box 28)
    - Intelligence service
    - Reports of
      - Bergery
      - Committee of Experts
      - Committee of Guarantees
    - Statistics
  - Rhineland (Box 29)
  - Rimbaud, Arthur
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D.
  - Rossi-Landi, Guy
  - Sauvages, Pierre
  - Scapini, Georges
  - Seine-et-Oise, Département de
    - Bulletin Officiel, 1943 June 18
    - Conseil General, 3 folders
    - Correspondence of Bergery as Deputy for the Department
    - Protection of sites
  - Soviet-Union - Non-aggression pact with Germany, 1939 August 23 (Box 30)
  - Stalin, Joseph
  - Stavisky, l'Affaire (and Chiappe)
  - Tardieu, André
  - Tixier-Vignancourt, Jean-Louis
  - Trecourt, Michel
  - Tunisia
  - Union pour la Défense de la Justice et de la Liberté
  - Unir, Paris
  - Vacher de Lapouge, G.
  - Versailles Peace Conference, 1919
  - Vu et Lu, Paris
  - Walter, Domenica and Jean
- LEGAL PRACTICE FILE, 1920s-1930s (Boxes 31-34)
  Briefs and other legal documents, and correspondence, arranged alphabetically by case title, usually the name of Bergery's client.
  - Abbas Hilmi Pacha (Box 31)
  - Abdul Hamid Khan II, 3 folders (Box 32)
  - Anglejan
  - Aragon/Martin du Gard (Box 33)
  - Didier
  - Ducreux/Amadou
  - Ford, Edsel B.
  - Ford Française - Dollfus, 2 folders
  - Gafenco
  - Hispano-Suiza
  - Karolyi/Dim
  - Kemp
  - Kent
  - Lacloche
  - Laforest
  - Lasell (Box 34)
  - Leroy-Ladurie - Procès de Castres, 2 folders
  - Maisonobe/Dugrenot
  - Manneville
  - Mer Morte, sels de brome dans la
  - Morand
  - Naldi
  - Nicolas
  - Schouwaloff
  - Sert
  - Société Meunière du Liban
  - Tailleur, Henri
  - Vapeur Beatsa
  - Vieil Antibes
  - Miscellaneous
- NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS, 1924-1962 (Boxes 35-44)
  Clippings mentioning Bergery or directly related to his career, arranged chronologically. See also BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, Trial.
  - 1924-1933 (Box 35)
  - 1925-1933
  - 1927-1928
  - 1929 (Box 36)
  - 1929-1936
  - 1931 (Box 37)
  - 1931-1932
  - 1932, 2 folders
  - 1932, 2 folders (Box 38)
  - 1932-1934
  - 1933-1934
  - 1934, 3 folders (Box 39)
  - 1934, 2 folders (Box 40)
  - 1934-1935
  - 1934-1937
  - 1935
  - 1935 (Box 41)
  - 1936
  - 1936-1938
  - 1937, 2 folders
  - 1937 (Box 42)
  - 1938
  - 1939
  - 1939-1940
  - 1940
  - 1941, 2 folders (Box 43)
  - 1942, 3 folders
  - 1943
  - 1943-1947
  - 1949-1952
  - 1956-1962
  - Articles in which Bergery was misrepresented and for which he sent rebuttals to the respective newspapers (Box 44)
    Mostly correspondence, legal papers, etc.
- PHOTOGRAPHS (Envelope mA)
  27 prints depicting Bergery and others (including one of him and Stavisky as children, posing for a grade school class picture); scenes of Chad and the French Alps; a 1931 civilian airplane; sketches of Bergery and of the Chamber of Deputies; 1 postcard of the Berlin Wall.